(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Birthday Live 2021
キセキ色のような毎日を
Every day is like a miracle,
君と過ごしたいよ
I want to spend them with you.
みんな！今日はときのそら誕生日2021に見に来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to see Tokino Sora's Birthday Live 2021 today!
wonderland
作詞・作曲：渡辺 翔
Lyrics/Composition: Sho Watanabe
一緒にいれば wonderland
When we're together, it's a wonderland.
楽しんでいってねー！
Please enjoy the show!
憧れてた夢に乗せて
Riding on the dreams I've longed for,
君の笑顔に会いに行きたいよ
I want to go see your smile.
大好きな気持ちだけ
Only these feelings of love,
変わらずに抱きしめて
I'll keep holding onto them forever.
魔法のようなきらめき
This magical sparkle,
ずっと感じていたいな
I want to feel it forever.
みんな、たくさんのコメント見えてるよ！ありがとう！
Everyone, I can see all your comments! Thank you!
今 奏でる奇跡のロマンティック
The miracle romantic playing now,
希望を見せて 明日へ駆け抜けて
Show me hope and run through to tomorrow.
So dreamy 集めてイルミネーション
So dreamy, gathering the illumination,
輝く夢のドア
The door to shining dreams.
明日はもっと世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow, the world will shine even more.
君次第さ wonderland
It's up to you, wonderland.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
冷めないで夢の世界　もっと飛び跳ねていたい
Don't let it end, this world of dreams... I want to keep hopping around even more
みんな行くよ！ジャンプ！
Everyone, here we go! Jump!
今ファンタスティック　奇跡のマジック
Now it's Fantastic, a magic of miracles
驚いて笑って泣いて聞いて
Be surprised, laugh, cry, and listen
ABC見せればエンターテイメント
If I show you the ABCs, it's entertainment
見つかる夢のチケット
Finding the ticket to our dreams
明日はまた世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow the world will shine again
君次第さ　さぁ、踊ろう
It's up to you, now let's dance
イメージしてみてごらん
Just try to imagine it
空も飛べるはずだよ
We should even be able to fly in the sky
君がいるこの世界は
In this world where you are,
愛が溢れる
it's overflowing with love.
今年も！無事！
This year too! I was able to safely!
お誕生日！迎えられたよ！
Celebrate my birthday!
みんなのおかげだ！
It's all thanks to everyone!
本当に本当にありがとう！
Thank you so, so much!
今ファンタスティック　奇跡のマジック
Now it's Fantastic, a magic of miracles
希望を見せて明日へと駆け抜けて
Show me hope and run toward tomorrow
So Dreaming　集めているイメージは
So Dreaming, the images I'm gathering are
鮮やかな夢のドレス
a bright dress of dreams
明日はまた世界は輝くよ
Tomorrow the world will shine again
君次第さ　さぁ、踊ろう
It's up to you, now let's dance
気になって
I'm curious
もっと私を見て　もっと
look at me more, more
恩返しは愛のこもった
My way of giving back is with a love-filled
投げキッスで
blown kiss
ファンサ
作詞・作曲 HoneyWorks
Fansa
Lyrics & Composition: HoneyWorks
黄色い声援　目が合ってるよ
Yellow cheers, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って　恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and please fall in love with me
やれること　何でもします
I'll do anything I can
神対応で虜にしちゃう
I'll captivate you with god-tier fan service
エゴサで見つけたアンチの声
The voices of antis I found while ego-searching
ふざけんな　誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me, I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫　ここに立てば
But it's okay, if I stand here,
みんながいる
everyone is here
行くよー！
Here we go!
君に会って　もっと私を見て　もっと
Meeting you, look at me more, more
恩返しは愛のこもった投げキッスで
My way of giving back is with a love-filled blown kiss
虜にする　もっと夢を見せる　もっと
I'll captivate you, show you more dreams, more
楽しませて　愛のこもったスペシャルな曲
Let me entertain you with a love-filled special song
もっともっと！楽しく叫んでねー！
More, more! Shout happily!
お手紙も　書いてください
Please write me letters too
何度も読んで　宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure
スキャンダル　まだ早いけど
Scandals, it's still too early but
裏切りません　宣言しときまーす
I won't betray you, I'll declare it now
執拗な嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to persistent harassment
ふざけんな　実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me, I'll win with my own strength
だからやめない　負けず嫌い
So I won't stop, the sore loser
私がいる
me is here
行くよー！
Here we go!
拳上げて　もっと汗をかいて　もっと
Raise your fists, sweat even more, more
恩返しは愛のこもった声掛けで
My way of giving back is with love-filled chants
大歓声　もっと　まだまだね　もっと
Loud cheers, more, not enough yet, more
受け止めてね　愛のこもったワガママソング
Please accept it, a love-filled selfish song
終わりが近づく　寂しいね
The end is near, it's lonely, isn't it?
楽しいのに　泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying
次も　次も　また会えるよね
Next time, and the time after that, we can meet again, right?
約束！
Promise!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
優しさに溢れている言葉も 心無い誰かの言葉さえも
Even words full of kindness, or the heartless words of someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強く成ろう
...are necessary, they're necessary to become strong.
好きに叫べ もっと楽しんじゃえ もっと
Shout out what you like, enjoy yourself more, even more.
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, may it be a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと 共に歩もう ずっと
Let's sing together, forever, let's walk together, forever.
合言葉は とびっきりの L-O-V-E
The watchword is the ultimate L-O-V-E!
好きになって もっと 私を見て もっと
Fall in love, look at me more, even more.
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
I'll repay you with a blow-kiss full of love.
虜にする もっと 夢を見せる もっと
I'll entrance you more, I'll show you dreams even more.
楽しんでいて 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Keep enjoying this special night full of love.
ファンサじゃぶ！
Fansajabu!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はーい！ということで皆さん、こんにちは！ときのそらです！
Yes! So, everyone, hello! I'm Tokino Sora!
今日皆さん、えっとえっと、ときのそら誕生日2021に来てくれてありがとうございます。
Everyone, um, thank you so much for coming to Tokino Sora Birthday 2021 today.
たくさんのコメントありがとう！見えてるよ、見えてるよ！
Thank you for all the comments! I see them, I see them!
やーすごいね！いや久しぶりにこのステージに来たんですけども、
Wow, amazing! It's been a while since I've been on this stage,
おーおーすごいよね！もうやっぱりさ、アリーナは最高だよ！
but wow, it's great! As expected, an arena is the best!
こんな素敵なステージに立つことができて私とっても幸せです。ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy to be able to stand on such a wonderful stage. Thank you very much.
お水を飲みたい。
I want to drink some water.
と、いうわけですね、えっと……
And so, um...
本日、ああなんか本当はね、今日ゲストのアリスちゃん、子兎音ちゃん、葵ちゃん、AZKiちゃんと……
Today, ah, actually, today with guests Alice-chan, Kotone-chan, Aoi-chan, and AZKi-chan...
えっと、子兎音ちゃんの後に「あ」が付いてる……今気づいた。
Wait, there's an "A" after Kotone-chan... I just noticed.
なんだけど、あのね、色んな事情があって今日は一人で舞台に立つことにはなっておりますが、
...but, you know, due to various circumstances, I'll be standing on stage alone today,
その代わりにね、ちょっと四人にはある方法でお手伝いをね、してもらおうと思っています。
but instead, I'm having the four of them help me out in a certain way.
ま、アリスちゃんはね、あの実は一緒に踊ってみたみたいな感じのをやる予定だったのでちょっとね、
Well, Alice-chan, we were actually planning to do a "tried dancing together" kind of thing, so...
うーん、悲しいって感じなんだけど、でもでも！
it's a bit sad, but, but!
本分たくさん盛り上げていこうかなと思っているのでぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
I want to liven things up a lot, so please look forward to it!
というわけですね、そんな私の大切なお友達からメッセージが届いております。こちらです！
And so, I've received messages from those precious friends of mine. Here they are!
ごきげんようです！そらちゃん！アリスだよ！お誕生日……
Greetings! Sora-chan! It's Alice! Happy...
おめでとうございまーす！ぱちぱちぱちー！
...Birthday! Clap clap clap!
祝っちゃうよ！おめでとうだよ、そらちゃん！
I'm celebrating! Congratulations, Sora-chan!
あの、も、そらちゃんはいつもいつも優しくて思いやりがあって、
You know, Sora-chan is always, always kind and considerate,
なんかアリスがこうやって話しかけるとそらちゃん「うん」って聞いてくれて、本当に本当に大好きです。
and whenever I talk to her like this, she listens with an "un-huh", I really, really love you.
あの、そらちゃんはね、どんなにおとなさんになったとしてもそのままのそらちゃんでいてください。
Sora-chan, no matter how much of an adult you become, please stay the way you are.
これからもいっぱいいっぱい仲良くしてもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if we can continue to be great friends.
本当に、本当に、おめでとう！
Truly, truly, congratulations!
う、嬉しい！
Oh, I'm so happy!
アリスちゃーん！メッセージありがとう！
Alice-chan! Thank you for the message!
そしてそして、アリスちゃんだけじゃなくもう一人からも来てますよ！しゅ！
And, and, it's not just Alice-chan, there's a message from one more person too! Swoosh!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
そらちゃんとは……はい！天神子兎音です！
With Sora-chan... Yes! I'm Tenjin Kotone!
えっと、そらちゃんとはですね、三年半のお付き合い……お付き合い？
Um, with Sora-chan, we've been going out for three and a half years... Going out?
お付き合いって……三年半お友達期間を経ているのですけれども、
Association... we've been friends for three and a half years,
...そとのイベントとか番組に出たときに
...when we appeared in an outside event or program,
お隣の席だったことから始まって
it all started from us sitting next to each other,
そこからずっとこうして一緒にね
and from there, we've always been together like this,
Vの界隈にいられることがすごく幸せだなって
and I'm very happy that we can be in the VTuber world together.
思っています。
That's how I feel.
ありがとう
Thank you!
最近はちょっとお互いの時間が合わなくて
Lately, our schedules haven't really matched up,
電話したりとか話したりとか配信一緒にやったりとかができてないけど
so we haven't been able to call, talk, or stream together,
そろそろ私も落ち着いてきたからまた一緒に何かしようね
but I've settled down a bit now, so let's do something together again.
はい！
Yes!
そらちゃんのこれからがもっともっと幸せであるように
I'm praying that Sora-chan's future
私も祈っております。
will be even more and more happy.
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、アリスちゃんとね、琴音ちゃんのメッセージでした。ありがとうございました！
So, that was a message from Alice-chan and Kotone-chan. Thank you so much!
でね、アリスちゃんとのダンスの曲はね、ちょっとね、ソロになっちゃったんですけど
And, the dance song with Alice-chan, well, it ended up being a solo,
今度ね、アリスちゃんの気持ちをグッと！グッと！自分の心の中に入れてパフォーマンスしていきたいと思います。
but I'm going to put Alice-chan's feelings deep inside me and perform.
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
エイリアンエイリアン、そしてコネクト、2曲連続です。
"Alien Alien" and then "Connect," two songs in a row.
どうぞ！
Here we go!
エイリアンエイリアン
作詞・作曲：ナユタン星人
Alien Alien
Lyrics/Composition: Nayutalien
ゆれる街灯 篠突く雨
Flickering streetlights, driving rain
振れる感情 感覚のテレパス
Swaying emotions, a telepath of senses
迷子のふたりはコンタクト
Two lost children make contact
心は恋を知りました
Our hearts have come to know love
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
どどどど どろのつぎはぎの制服
Mu-mu-mu-muddy, patched-up uniform
重度のミスコミュニケーション
Severe miscommunication
眼光 赤色キラキラ
Eyes gleaming red, sparkling
起こる胸騒ぎ
My heart is racing
みんな！ いくよ！
Everyone! Here we go!
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I am an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
Bewildering your heart
交ざりあう 宇宙の引力で
With the gravity of a merging universe
感じてる 気持ちはトキメキ
The feeling I have is a crush
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
引きあう心は逃れられない
Hearts pulling at each other can't escape
あなたに未体験のときめき
An unexperienced crush on you
見せるわ
I'll show you
好きよ
I love you
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
皆さん知ってる人はコメントしてもらえると嬉しいです！ いくよー！
If you know the song, I'd love to see your comments! Here we go!
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
Fluorescent lights flickering on and off
超常な混沌が静かにあなたを蝕んだ
Supernatural chaos quietly consumed you
並行な信号は特異点に交わった
Parallel signals met at a singularity
創造現実盲信症
Creative reality blind-faith syndrome
シンドローム 独りきり夜な夜な空想
Syndrome, fantasizing all alone night after night
描く まるで何処にもありはしない
Drawing, like it doesn't exist anywhere
抒情を叫ぶ不要な気まで
Shouting lyricism, even unnecessary feelings
あなたは全てを知りたい
You want to know everything
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I am an alien
あなたの心を惑わせる
Bewildering your heart
瞳に映らない引力に
By a gravity unseen by the eye
気づいたの わたしは
I've realized it
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, your alien
触れあえば傷は二度と消えない
If we touch, the scars will never fade
降りそそぐ 未体験の光線
Showering unexperienced rays of light
トキメク心には届かない
Won't reach a heart in love
エイリアン 二人はエイリアン
Alien, the two of us are aliens
高鳴る気持ちは抑えられない
I can't suppress these racing feelings
あなたは未体験のときめき
An unexperienced crush on you
贈るわ
I'll give it to you
好きよ
I love you
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to make sure
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the surging darkness and move forward
コネクト
作詞・作曲：渡辺 翔
Connect
Lyrics/Composition: Sho Watanabe
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see
私ここでまた見ることできるの？
the lost future here again?
…るの
...ing
溢れ出した不安の影を
The shadows of overflowing anxiety
何度でも咲いてこの世界歩んでいこう
Blooming time and again, let's walk through this world
止めどなく刻まれた
Incessantly engraved
時は今始まり告げ
Time now signals the beginning
変わらない思いを乗せ
Carrying unchanging feelings
閉ざされた扉開けよう
Let's open the closed door
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart began to run
未来を描くため
To paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path
空は綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれる
The sky, in its beautiful blue, is always waiting for me
だから怖くない　もう何があっても
So I'm not afraid, no matter what happens anymore
挫けない
I won't give up
振り返れば仲間がいて
Looking back, my friends are there
気が付けば優しく包まれてた
And before I knew it, I was gently enveloped
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything is distorted
唯一信じれるここが救いだった
This place, the only thing I can believe in, was my salvation
喜びも悲しみも
Both joy and sadness
分け合えば強まる思い
Feelings that strengthen when shared
この声が届くのなら
If this voice can reach you
きっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
Then surely a miracle can happen
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
Closing my eyes, I confirm it
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
Shaking off the encroaching darkness, I'll move forward
どんなに大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is
超えてみせるからきっと
I'll show you I can overcome it, surely
明日信じて祈って
Believing in tomorrow, I pray
AZKiちゃん、ありがとう！
AZKi-chan, thank you!
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in a broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
...reached here as if drawn in
目覚めた心は走り出した
My awakened heart began to run
未来を描くため
To paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path
空は綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれる
The sky, in its beautiful blue, is always waiting for me
だから怖くない　もう何があっても
So I'm not afraid, no matter what happens anymore
挫けない
I won't give up
ずっと明日待って
Always waiting for tomorrow
えへっ。
Ehe.
というわけで、『エイリアンエイリアン』、そしてですね、
So that was "Alien Alien", and...
AZKiちゃんと一緒に歌いました、『コネクト』でした！ ありがとうございます！
...we sang together with AZKi-chan, it was "Connect"! Thank you very much!
いや、ということでね、今回は、えー、『歌のプレゼント』をいただいたので、
Well, so, this time, since I received a "Singing Present"...
まあね、デュエットみたいな感じでちょっと演出ができたらいいなと思って、
...I thought it would be nice to have a performance like a duet...
こちらでね、こう、一緒にデュエットみたいな感じの演出になっています。
...so we have this performance where we're singing a duet together.
いや、なんかね、『コネクト』は一度ね、AZKiちゃんとも歌ったことのある曲で、
You know, "Connect" is a song I've sung with AZKi-chan before...
すごく思い出深かったので、私の方から、
...and it was very memorable, so from my side...
おぉ、ありがとう！ ...から、ちょっと一緒にね、歌いたいなみたいな話をしたんですよ。
Oh, thank you! ...I suggested that I wanted to sing it together with her.
ねぇ、今回ね、本当にギリギリになっちゃったんですけど、
You know, it was really last minute this time...
こんな感じでプレゼントもらえて本当に嬉しかったし、
...but I was really happy to receive a present like this,
こう、なんか、みんなの、絆の強さを、こう、感じることができたというか、
and I felt the strength of everyone's bond, or rather...
あー、なんか、すごい素敵な仲間に恵まれてるなと思って、
...I felt that I'm blessed with such wonderful friends,
なんか、とても、なんか、嬉しい感じになりました。ありがとうございます。
and it made me feel very, well, happy. Thank you so much.
なんね、今日はゲストが4人いるということなので
So, since there are four guests today...
まだね、半分なんですよ。半分。
it's still only halfway. Halfway.
次、誰かのメッセージ来てるんだよ。
Next, there's a message from someone.
誰だと思う？どっちだと思う？
Who do you think it is? Which one do you think?
早速見てみようか。
Let's take a look right away.
この方です！
It's this person!
あー！
Ah!
こんそめ！
Konsome!
あずきちだー！
It's Azukichi!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Sora-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
AZKiです。えー、去年の誕生日から早1年ですね。
I'm AZKi. It's already been a year since your last birthday.
こういう大変な状況の中でも、SorAZで一緒にゲームをしたり、
Even in these difficult times, we played games together as SorAZ,
二人のね、オリジナル曲を作ったり、
created our own original songs,
そう、そうなんだよ。
Yes, that's right.
刹那ティックコード、劇場版SorAZがあったり、
like Setsunatic Code, and the Movie Version SorAZ...
劇場版ね。
Movie version.
クリスマス会もしたね。
We also had a Christmas party.
したね。
We did.
えーと、そのあとは... そう、あの、マイクラをね、めっちゃそらちゃんが誘ってくれて、
And after that... yeah, Sora-chan, you invited me to play Minecraft so much,
AZKiがマイクラ始めたりとか、
that I actually started playing Minecraft.
うん。
Yeah.
本当にそらちゃんと過ごしたこの1年間、楽しい思い出がいっぱいです。
This past year spent with you has been full of fun memories.
本当に本当にありがとう。
Truly, thank you so much.
というわけで今日はね、えー、そらちゃんとあの曲と...
So today, I want to sing that song with Sora-chan...
...そらちゃんとあの曲、そしてあの曲を歌いたい...
...sing that song, and that song, with Sora-chan...
あはは、あの曲？
Haha, that song?
...よね？
...right?
あれ？あれ？あの曲？
Huh? Huh? That song?
ねー、みんなも聴きたいよね？
Hey, everyone wants to hear it too, right?
ね！
Right!
それでは改めて、そらちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！これからも仲良くしてね。
So once again, Sora-chan, Happy Birthday! Let's continue to be good friends.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして今年も1年、素敵な年にしてください。
And please have a wonderful year ahead.
それでは、AZKiでした！ルンあー！
That was AZKi! Lun-ah!
ルンあー！
Lun-ah!
はい、ということでAZKiちゃんからメッセージもらったよ。
Alright, so I got a message from AZKi-chan.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
嬉しいな、嬉しいな。
I'm so happy, so happy.
もう嬉しくてなんかもうこの後行きたくない感じ... 嘘。
I'm so happy I don't even want to continue... Just kidding.
それでは、この後の曲いきましょうか。
Now, let's get into the next song.
今ね、「この曲とこの曲」って言ってたんですけど、
She said "this song and that song" just now,
私たちにはですね、オリジナル曲が2つあります。
but we actually have two original songs.
その2つをですね、メドレーで歌っていきたいと思います。
We're going to sing those two as a medley.
まず1曲目、こちらです。
First up, here it is.
刹那ティックコード。
Setsunatic Code.
刹那ティックコード
作詞：高瀬愛虹 作曲・編曲：渡部チェル
Setsunatic Code
Lyrics: Aiko Takase Composer/Arranger: Cheru Watanabe
いつだって 未来のためばかりに
Always, just for the sake of the future
「今」という時間を費やすけれど
Spending this time called "now"
今だけは 今だけは 感じあうことができたら
If only for now, if only for now, we could feel each other
蓋をして 断ち切った 心がもう一度 動き出すよ
My heart, once shut tight and cut off, starts to move once more
震え出しそうな
Looking like it's about to tremble
胸の痛みも 涙の理由(わけ)も すべて
The pain in my chest, the reason for my tears, everything
強さに変えて
Change it into strength
飲み込んだ想い 仰いだ空に 飛ばせ
Let the feelings I swallowed fly into the sky I gazed up at
繋がるメロディ 流れる星に 重なって
A connecting melody, overlapping with the shooting stars
君のために歌うよ 君に届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it reaches you
輝きは世界線を超えて
The radiance crosses world lines
確かにここで響き合えた鼓動
The heartbeats that surely resonated together here
触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
The touching sounds turn into light and pour down
この一瞬が永遠だと
That this moment is eternal
きらめいては色づいていく 君と描いた世界
Gleaming and taking on color, the world I drew with you
いつだって 明日は来るだなんて
Thinking that tomorrow will always come
来て欲しくない朝もあるけれど
There are mornings I don't want to arrive
夜の闇 息潜め このまま隠れられなくて
Holding my breath in the darkness of night, unable to stay hidden like this
静寂を 断ち切って 叫びたい声を 歌に変えた
Cutting through the silence, I turned the voice that wanted to scream into a song
いつもそこにある
It's always there
隔て阻む壁も壊して 進め
Break through the walls that separate and block, and move forward
胸の奥にある
Deep inside my chest
忘れたフリで誤魔化しきれない傷も
The wounds I can't fully hide by pretending to forget
乗り越えてゆく
I will overcome them
絡まった想い 音に変えて 飛ばせ
Turn tangled thoughts into sound and let them fly
生まれるメロディ 激しく鼓動 奏で合う
A born melody, heartbeats intensely playing together
言葉だけじゃ足りない 歌じゃなきゃ届かない
Words alone are not enough, only a song can reach
情熱が胸を熱くさせて
Passion makes my chest burn hot
確かにここで分かり合えた鼓動
The heartbeats that surely understood each other here
時の流れを逆らうように
As if defying the flow of time...
...見られる
...be seen
何度だって歌うから
Because I'll sing any number of times
君の場所がいつか光に包み込まれるように
So that your place will one day be enveloped in light
全てが崩れ落ちそうで
When it feels like everything is falling apart
どこにも足踏み出せない時は
And you can't take a step anywhere
送り続けるこの言葉
I'll keep sending these words
聴こえる場所探し踏み出すよ
Searching for a place where they can be heard and stepping forward
飲み込んだ想い青い空に飛ばせ
Let your swallowed feelings fly into the blue sky
繋がるメロディ流れる星に止まっていく
The connecting melody stops at the shooting stars
君のために歌うよ
I'll sing for you
君に届くようにと
So that it reaches you
輝きは世界中を越えていく
The radiance transcends the world
確かにここで重ね合えた鼓動
The heartbeats that certainly synchronized here
触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
The touching sounds turn into light and pour down
この一瞬が永遠だと
That this moment is eternal
煌めいては色付いていく
Sparkling and taking on color
君と描いた世界
The world I drew with you
君と描く音が飛び出す
The sounds I draw with you fly out
刹那ティックコードまで
Up to the Setsuna Tick Code
紅藍クロニクル 作詞・作曲 AZKi
Kurenai Chronicle Lyrics & Composition: AZKi
いつの間に隠れた無数の星よ
Oh, countless stars that hid before I knew it
今君はどこで輝いているんだろう
Where are you shining now, I wonder?
今夜を彷徨う無数の旅路
Countless journeys wandering through tonight
今僕をどこへ連れて行くよ
Where will they take me now?
僕らが出会うため 世界中で
In order for us to meet, throughout the world
共に生きてくため 二人きり
In order to live together, just the two of us
ただこの空の先 どこまでも
Just beyond this sky, forever
呼び覚ませ心にあるものを
Awaken what is in your heart
殻を破り飛び立つように
Like breaking out of a shell and taking flight
果てない青が闇を貫く 煌めく光になれ
The endless blue pierces the darkness, become a sparkling light
悲しさよ 寂しさの 雨打たれても
Oh sadness, oh loneliness, even if struck by rain
辿り着く音 確かなメロディ それはきっと嘘じゃないよ
The sound that arrives, a certain melody, it's surely not a lie
ここでいつまでもいつまでも 二人歌い合おう
Here, forever and ever, let's sing together
誰にも見せない 弱さがほら
Look, the weakness I show to no one
こぼれては力に変わっていくから
Is overflowing and turning into strength
誰かを信じる 勇気を持って
Have the courage to believe in someone
振り切って 前へと進むだけだ
Shake it off and just move forward
僕らの存在は バーチャルで
Our existence is virtual
ふわりなんて言わせない リアルなんだ
Won't let anyone say it's vague, it's real
だってこの魂は 本物だ
Because this soul is the real thing
打ち砕け理不尽も常識も
Smash the absurdity and common sense
壁を超えて逆らうように
Like crossing walls and defying
果てない赤が闇を貫く 脈打つ血汐になれ
The endless red pierces the darkness, become pulsing lifeblood
愛おしさや 切なさも 覚えていくの
I'll learn about love and sadness too
作り出す音 確かなハーモニー これは生きた証だから
The sound created, a certain harmony, because this is proof of having lived
声を聴かせてよ 聴かせてよ 二人歌い合おう
Let me hear your voice, let me hear it, let's sing together
美しく 燃え上がる 炎よ
Beautifully blazing flame,
あぁ 夜空へ と咲く 花よ
Oh, flower blooming in the night sky.
互いに 目と目 合わせて
Meeting each other eye to eye,
互いに 手と手 重ねて
Joining each other hand in hand,
共に歌え 叫べ 鳴らせ 今 あぁ
Sing together, shout, let it ring out now, ah!
果てない愛は 僕ら貫く
Endless love pierces through us,
消えない記憶 皆で
with memories that won't fade, everyone,
愛しさよ 切なさを 抱えたままで
while embracing our love and sadness.
辿り着く音 確かなメロディ これは生きた証だから
The reaching sound, a steady melody, because this is proof that we lived.
今も
Even now,
燃えている 聞こえてるよ 二人だけの歌よ
it's burning, I can hear it, the song for just the two of us.
はい！というわけで
Yes! And so...
AZKiちゃんと歌ったのは、『紅藍クロニクル』、
The two songs I sang with AZKi-chan were 'Kouai Chronicle',
そして『レゾナディコード』の2曲でした。ありがとう！
and 'Resonadi Code'. Thank you!
いやあもう、この2つの曲はね、私の中ではすごい挑戦というか、
Well, these two songs were a big challenge for me,
あんまりね、普段その、カッコいい曲を歌っていなかったので
since I don't usually sing such cool songs.
なんかすごく、頑張ったなっていう...
I feel like I really gave it my all...
想いがある曲というか。
They are songs full of sentiment.
まあね、AZKiちゃんとはね、あの、それぞれ一人一人活動してるときに、
You see, with AZKi-chan, while we were each doing our solo activities,
一緒にね、頑張っていこう、頑張っていこうって
we'd encourage each other to keep doing our best.
一緒にこう、切磋琢磨してきた仲なんですけども
We've been friends who've grown together through friendly rivalry.
そんなAZKiちゃんとの曲を、こう一緒に歌うことができて、こういう形ですが、とっても嬉しいなと思いました。
I'm so happy that I could sing AZKi-chan's songs with her, even in this form.
AZKiちゃんがこれ作ってるんだよ、すごいよね！もう、才能にあふれてるよ。
AZKi-chan even composed these, isn't that amazing? She's just overflowing with talent.
お水飲むね、ちょっと。急に水飲みたいタイプ。
I'm going to drink some water now. I'm the type who suddenly wants water.
よいしょ。よいしょってなんだ。
Heave-ho. What even is 'heave-ho'?
というわけでね、お水ありがとう、みんな。
So, thank you for the water, everyone.
まあね、AZKiちゃんの曲2つはね、自分でも、あ、歌いやすいキーにはなっていたので
Anyway, both of AZKi-chan's songs were in a key that was easy for me to sing.
今までこう歌った中では一番、こう安心して歌えたなーっていう感じもしますし、こうね
So among all the songs I've sung, I felt the most at ease singing these.
ここにね、ずっとAZKiちゃんがね、見守ってると思ったら、なんか...
And knowing AZKi-chan was right here watching over me...
リラックスしちゃった、今。リラックスしすぎて、今、まったり喋ってるんですけど。
I've become so relaxed. I'm too relaxed and speaking quite leisurely now.
まあね、まったり喋ってるわけにもいかないぞと、いうわけでですね
Well, I can't just keep chatting leisurely. So...
最後のメッセージ、行きましょうか。歌いやすいです、歌いやすいです、全然。高い、高いかな？
Let's go to the last message. It's easy to sing, totally. Is it high? Maybe?
私の『エリアエリア』よりは低いから。でも全然、どの曲も歌いやすい曲を選んでるんですけど、ライブなので。
It's lower than my 'Alien Alien'. But I always choose songs that are easy to sing for lives.
あ、そういうこと言ってる場合じゃない。次のメッセージ、見てみましょう！ドン！
Ah, I shouldn't be saying that. Let's look at the next message! Bam!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
気合入ってる！えのぐに気合入ってる！ありがとう、イェーイ！
(Sora: You're so pumped! Enogu is so pumped! Thank you, yay!)
今日は、大事な生誕祭に呼んでくれてありがとう。
Thank you for inviting me to your important birthday celebration today.
そらちゃんとの一番の思い出は、歌...
My best memory with Sora-chan is singing...
と、言いたいところだけど
is what I'd like to say, but...
前にね、お絵かきコラボしたときに、
When we did that drawing collab before,
そらちゃんが描いた得体のしれない
that mysterious something Sora-chan drew,
ザリガニのような何かが、今でも脳裏にこびりついて離れません。
that crayfish-like something is still burned into my mind and won't leave.
そらちゃんはよくモノマネされることが非常に多いと思うんだけど
Sora-chan, I think you get impersonated quite a lot,
蒼は、どうしても、何回練習しても、そらちゃんのモノマネがうまくできません。
but Aoi, no matter how many times I practice, I just can't do a good impression of you.
でも今日は、大事なお誕生日なので、
But since today is your big birthday,
全集中、ときの呼吸、参の型で、モノマネしたいと思いまーす！
I'll give it my all! 'Time Breathing, Third Form'! I'm going to do an impression!
耳の穴かっぽじって...違うわ、
Clean out your ears... wait, no.
ぜひ聞いてね。
Please listen.
ときのそらです！
I'm Tokino Sora!
いやあ、似てたかなあ？
Well, did I sound like her?
それでは、そらちゃん、本当にお誕生日
Anyway, Sora-chan, a very happy
おめでとうございます！富士葵でした！
birthday to you! This was Fuji Aoi!
あおいちゃん、ありがとう！
Aoi-chan, thank you!
なんかいろいろ突っ込みどころのあるメッセージだったんだけど、
It was a message with many things to poke fun at,
すごく、すごくあおいちゃんらしいなと思って、
but it felt very much like Aoi-chan,
嬉しいなって思いました。
and it made me very happy.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ときのそら、さんのほうって言ってた？
Did she say "Mr./Ms. Tokino Sora"?
ウーイェイ！とかもすごかったね。
The "Woo, yay!" part was amazing too.
そんなあおいちゃんとはね、実はね、あるデュエット曲を歌いたいなと思ってるんですよ。
Actually, I've been wanting to sing a duet song with Aoi-chan.
うーん、なんだと思う？
Hmm, what do you think it is?
初めて二人で歌うので、ぜひぜひ皆さん、
It's our first time singing together, so everyone, please...
しっかり耳の穴かっぽじ...、
...clean out your ears and...
いや、ぜひ聞いてください。
No, please just listen.
それでは二人で歌います。
Now, we will sing together.
チューリングラブ。
Turing Love.
ほら恋の定義が分かんない
Look, I don't know the definition of love.
まず好きの基準も分かんない
First, I don't know the criteria for "liking."
要はこうしてるときが恋らしい
Basically, it seems this is what love is.
客観。証拠。 Evidence, please!
Objectivity. Evidence. Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved with calculations.
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve normal calculations.
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
Basically, it seems that state is what love is.
I know. 言う脳。 期待値以上の
I know. Speaking brain. Beyond expectation.
辞書に置いてＱがあって　Ａを出して解けるのに
In a dictionary, there's a Q, and you give an A to solve it, but...
勘違って　間違い合って　解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
Misunderstanding, making mistakes, what is this feeling without an answer?
Choice is meidou That's emotion
Choice is clear. That's emotion.
相対性にして　チューリングラブ
Make it relativity, Turing Love.
見つめ合ったって解けないメロウ
A mellow that won't be solved even if we stare at each other.
ワットイズラブ
What is love?
いまワン・ツー・スリーで明かそうか
Shall we reveal it now with a one-two-three?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
A question created with words.
吐息で赤くなるアンサー
An answer that turns red with a breath.
測ったって確定させて　僕らのBPM
Measure it and let's define our BPM.
チューリングラブ
Turing Love.
中に舞ったって信じないけど
Even if it dances inside, I won't believe it.
ロットイズラブ
What is love?
いまはABCから手繰りそうだ
Now it seems I'll trace it from ABC.
なんでか教えておくれよ
Tell me why.
想像させてよフェルマー
Make me imagine, Fermat.
予測不能な生命に触れてみる
I'll try touching an unpredictable life.
さあ証明しよう
Now, let's prove it.
間違いのないように証明しよう
Let's prove it so there are no mistakes.
この感情全部全部証明しよう
Let's prove all, all of these emotions.
正解があるなら証明しよう
If there's a correct answer, let's prove it.
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
到底証明したい証
A proof I desperately want to prove.
目に見えない無理難題を
An invisible, impossible challenge...
ASAP 導き出したい
I want to derive it ASAP.
辿り着きたい最適解へ
I want to reach the optimal solution.
何度絡まったって　ぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times we get tangled or clash...
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です
Even the process of unraveling this mysterious anomaly is a necessary condition.
3次元（カッコ立体）における2点AB間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between two points A and B in 3D (solid geometry).
式の公式だと思ってたのに
Even though I thought it was a formula for the expression...
座標も公式も見当たらないし
I can't find the coordinates or the formula...
参考資料にも載っていないから　君と生み出して見せたいじゃん
Since it's not in the reference materials, I want to create it with you.
3次元（カッコ世界）におけるこの気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in 3D (the world).
まるだってバツだって不和にとってイコールで
Whether it's a circle or an X, it's an equal for discord...
近くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちの針を
The needle of this feeling that swings as it gets closer and further...
条件は明瞭
The conditions are clear.
ステップエモーション
Step emotion.
相対性にして　チューリングラブ
Make it relativity, Turing Love.
吐き出した胸の痛くなるほど
To the point where my chest hurts from breathing it out.
証明は今も角度増しているようだ
The proof seems to be gaining angle even now.
あいまいもじょかして
Making it ambiguous...
使いたいの仮説を
I want to use the hypothesis.
いま二人なら実証できそう
Now, if it's the two of us, we might be able to demonstrate it.
チューリングラブ
Turing Love.
見つめ合ったって切りないメロウ
A mellow that's endless even if we stare at each other.
ワットイズラブ
What is love?
いまワン・ツー・スリーで明かそうか
Shall we reveal it now with a one-two-three?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
A question created with words.
吐息で赤くなるアンサー
An answer that turns red with a breath.
測ったって確定させて　僕らのBPM
Measure it and let's define our BPM.
チューリングラブ
Turing Love.
あおいちゃん！
Aoi-chan!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
映像もプレゼントしてくれた、
She even presented me with a video,
あおいちゃん！
Aoi-chan!
見てたよ！
I saw it!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
やー、みんな、みんなすごくこう、
Everyone, everyone has been so...
私の、こう何て言うんだろう、お誕生日に協力してくれて、
helpful for my, what should I call it, birthday,
もう感謝でいっぱいです。
and I'm just full of gratitude.
あー、嬉しいね。
Ah, I'm so happy.
さあ、というわけでですね、ゲストコーナー終わりました。皆さん！
So, with that, the guest corner has finished. Everyone!
とっても最高なお誕生日だったし、こんなにたくさんの皆さんと、こう...
It's been the best birthday ever, and being able to spend time with so many of you like this...
みんなとね、こう、一緒の時間を過ごすことができて、本当に幸せだったなって思います。
Spending this time together with all of you, I feel truly happy.
Thank you for... Thank you...
パチパチ everyone! パチパチ everyoneって何？
Pachi-pachi everyone! What is "pachi-pachi everyone"?
Clap everyone, thank you! Thank you!
ということでですね、お誕生日、本当に最高の...
So, my birthday, this truly amazing...
ライブに、みんなのおかげで、もちろん...
live, thanks to everyone, and of course...
一緒に協力してくれたゲストのみんな、そして、ここにいるスタッフの皆さん、ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
the guests who collaborated with me, and the staff here, thank you very much. Thank you.
そして、何よりも、ここに応援してくださっている皆さんの、おかげだなって思ってます。
And above all, I feel it's all thanks to everyone who supports me.
本当にみんな、今日はありがとう！
Truly, thank you all for today!
そしてそして、最後になるんですが、えー、最後の曲の前に、ちょっとですね...
And then, finally, before the last song, just a little bit...
告知？急になんか告知みたいになっちゃったんですけど。
An announcement? Suddenly it's turned into like an announcement section.
えー、私お誕生日ということで、えー、記念グッズの方を、えー、出させていただくことになりました！
Um, since it's my birthday, I'll be releasing some commemorative goods!
それが、こちらです！
And here they are!
はい、ときのそら誕生日記念2021。5月15日販売開始ということで、このあと21時から販売させていただきます。
Yes, Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration 2021. Sales start May 15th, so they'll be available from 9:00 PM tonight.
えー、そちらの方はですね、セットになっておりまして、記念ボイス1種、そしてですね、記念グッズ3種セット。
Those come in a set: one commemorative voice pack and a set of three commemorative goods.
そしてですね、直筆サイン入りで、ま、数量限定なんですけども、おるだん先生描き下ろしのイラストポストカードの方をご用意しております。
And, although it's limited in quantity, we have an illustration postcard by Ordan-sensei with my handwritten signature.
えー、こちらの方はですね、ぜひぜひ、あの、このあと21時からということなので、気になる方は見ていただけると嬉しいです。
Please check them out starting from 9:00 PM if you're interested.
ま、一つ一つのものを、ちょっと見ていきましょう。こちらです。
Well, let's take a look at each item. Here it is.
まずこちら、オリジナルCDの名前が「くもはれ」ということでですね。
First, this original CD titled "KumoHurray".
これから歌う「くもはれ」の曲なんですけども、こちらの曲は私が作詞しまして、赤ティンさんに作曲していただきました。
The song "KumoHurray" which I'm about to sing, I wrote the lyrics for it, and Akatin-san composed the music.
えー、そしてですね、2つ目のは「花時の空」という曲なんですけども、こちら「このめどきのそら」と言ってですね...
And the second one is a song called "Hanadoki no Sora"... or "Konomedoki no Sora"...
本当にまだ一人ぼっちで寂しいなあと思いながらやっていた時に、ロジカルロジックさんという方から提供された曲です。
It's a song provided by Logical Logic-san from back when I was just starting out and feeling a bit lonely.
それをですね、フルバージョンで収録しております。
We've recorded the full version of it.
そちらのあとインストも入っている全4曲になっております。
It also includes instrumental versions, making it a 4-track release.
そしてそして、続いてはこちら！
And next, this!
こちらがですね、単品でも買えるようになっておりまして。
You can also buy these individually.
こちらの方はですね、ミニぬいぐるみにまっております。
This is a mini plushie.
やっぱね、こう、今までのぬいぐるみと違って、ちょっとちっちゃめなんですよね。だから、なんか...
Unlike the previous plushies, it's a bit smaller. So, like...
机に飾れるやつもあるし、大きいそらちゃんに囲まれてちっちゃいぬいぐるみポンって乗っけてこう遊んでもらっても嬉しいですし...
you can display it on your desk, or place it among bigger Sora-chan plushies and play with it like that...
カバンに付けてもらっても嬉しいかな、ということで、ぬいぐるみ、みたいな感じで飾ってもらえたらいいなと思いまして、こちらに出しました！
I'd also be happy if you attached it to your bag. I released this hoping you'd decorate with lots of plushies!
はい、そして続いてはこちら！
Yes, and next is this!
これすごくない？おるだん先生描き下ろし両面クリアファイル！これももちろん単品で買えますよ。
Isn't this amazing? A double-sided clear file drawn by Ordan-sensei! You can buy this individually too.
両面すごい可愛いでしょう？テンションが上がってる、ふわーっとしてる私と、あと...
Both sides are so cute, right? There's the high-tension, airy version of me, and...
「花時の空」をイメージした私のクリアファイルの両面になっておりますので、ぜひぜひ使っていただけたら嬉しいなと。
the version based on "Hanadoki no Sora". Since it's double-sided, I'd be happy if you used it.
学校とか会社とかで使いやすいかなと思って、A4のクリアファイルになっておりますので、ぜひぜひちょっと見てみてください。
I thought it'd be easy to use at school or work, as it's an A4 clear file. Please take a look.
私もこれ何個か買って一個使う。
I'll buy a few and use one myself.
そして続いてが、こちら！
And next is this!
こちらはですね、記念ボイスですね。記念ボイスだけで買えるのかな？
This is the commemorative voice pack. Can you buy just the voice pack too?
ボイスの方と、あと全部セットの方は、数量限定になっております。これ全部合わせたものになりますね。
There's the voice pack, and the full set which is limited in quantity. This combines everything.
そちらの方は直筆でサイン書かせていただきますので、ぜひぜひ興味ある方はよろしくお願いします！
For the set, I'll be handwriting the signatures, so if you're interested, please check it out!
はい！
Yes!
と、そんな感じです。皆さん、わかったかな？
And that's about it. Did you all get that?
「頑張って」って言われてる、何を？何を頑張って？
Someone's saying "Good luck". Good luck with what? What should I work hard at?
ときのそら 誕生日記念2021
5月15日 販売開始
記念ボイス1種 / 記念グッズ3種セット / 直筆サイン入りイラストポストカード
Tokino Sora Birthday Celebration 2021
Sales start May 15th
1 Commemorative Voice / 3 Commemorative Goods / Illustration Postcard with Signature
オリジナルCD『くもはれ』
収録楽曲: 01. KumoHurray! 02. 花時の空
Original CD "KumoHurray"
Tracklist: 01. KumoHurray! 02. Hanadoki no Sora
ときのそら ミニぬいぐるみ
サイズ: 高さ約15cm
Tokino Sora Mini Plushie
Size: Approx. 15cm tall
おるだん先生描き下ろし両面クリアファイル
サイズ: 21.0cm × 29.7cm
Double-sided Clear File drawn by Ordan-sensei
Size: 21.0cm x 29.7cm
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えっと、
Um,
わぁ、星！
Wow, stars!
あ、ありがとう、みんな。
Ah, thank you, everyone.
というわけでね、21時から、
So, from 9 PM,
えー、
uh,
ずっとみんな見て待ってもらえれば嬉しいなと思います。
I hope you'll all watch and wait for it.
そして、そしてそしてそして！
And, and and and!
次歌う曲えー、はですね、
The next song I'm going to sing...
その2曲のうちの「KumoHurray!」の方を歌わせていただきます。
...is "KumoHurray!" from those two songs.
こちらの方はですね、えー、掛け声がすごいいっぱいになっています。
This one has a lot of call-and-response.
今日初めて歌うので何とも言えないと思うんですけど、
It's my first time singing it today, so I'm not sure,
掛け声気づいたらなんか、なんかコメントしてもらえたらとっても嬉しいです。
but I'd be very happy if you could comment if you notice the calls.
すごい難しい曲なので頑張って歌います！
It's a very difficult song, so I'll do my best to sing it!
それでは、もう最後の曲いっちゃって大丈夫ですかね？
Now, is it okay to move on to the last song?
最後の曲、いこうと思います。
I'm going to do the last song.
今日初公開させていただきます、
Making its debut today,
KumoHurray!
KumoHurray! 作詞：ときのそら 作曲・編曲：赤ティン
KumoHurray! Lyrics: Tokino Sora, Composition/Arrangement: Akatin
Na na na na na na na na na na na na...
空へ進め
Advance to the sky
この曲いっぱい掛け声あるので、一緒にやっていきましょう！
There are a lot of calls in this song, so let's do it together!
フワフワとリズムに合わせて
Move fluffy to the rhythm
ステップ踏んでこうどこまでも
Let's step forward to anywhere
ほら羽ばたいていけそう
Look, I feel like I can take flight
さあ 助走期 ワクワク
Now, the approach phase, exciting
胸が高鳴るよ
My heart is racing
この思いはもう止まらない
These feelings won't stop anymore
みんな元気に行こうよ
Everyone, let's go energetically
大きな声出してさ 叫ぼう
Raise your voice and shout
心が軽くなっていくからさ
Because your heart will get lighter
君の心は 曇りのち晴れ渡って
Your heart will clear up after the clouds
虹をかけるよ
And form a rainbow
胸を張って 今を進もう
Hold your head high and advance through the now
星のように 輝いて
Shine like a star
呼吸合わせて 気持ち呼んでこう
Sync our breaths and call out our feelings
いたずらをし合えたらいいよね
It'd be nice if we could play pranks on each other
ちょっと下手だね 嘘だよ
You're a bit bad at it, just kidding
些細な会話で 私たちは今
Through trivial conversations, we are now
分かり合おう
Understanding each other
超えていこう あの時の空よりも
Let's go beyond, further than the sky of that time
もっと遠くまで
To somewhere even further
みんなほっとけないからね
Because I can't leave anyone behind
さあ 止まらないで
Now, don't stop
上の空にならないで
Don't be absent-minded
歩けたなら ゆっくりでも道はできる
If you can walk, even slowly, a path will be made
夢の色 描いて
Draw the colors of your dreams
みんな！今日はお誕生日お祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for celebrating my birthday today!
すっごい楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
曇りがちな気分も
Even when you feel cloudy
ちょっと目線を変えたのなら
If you change your perspective a bit
心はればれ
Your heart will be clear and bright
あの子になれるかもよ
Maybe you can become that person
一人じゃないよ
You're not alone,
不安になったらここに来ればいいよ
if you feel anxious, just come here
私はずっと待っているからね
Because I'll always be waiting
負けてもいい
It's okay to lose,
頑張ってきたことは無駄じゃないから
what you've worked hard for isn't in vain
胸を張って 今を生きよう
Hold your head high and live in the now
星のように 輝いて
Shine like a star
みんな！最後もいくよー！
Everyone! Let's go for the end too!
Na na na na na na na na na na na na...
空へ進め
Advance to the sky
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
Birthday Live 2021
Special Guest: AZKi, Hoshimachi Suisei,
Inugami Korone, Akai Haato, 夜空メル
Inugami Korone, Akai Haato, Yozora Mel